

☑ DruSerkes@gmail.com ③ druserkes 🦶 203-912-2047 🧿 New York, NY in dru-serkes 🦸 druserkes

### **SUMMARY**

Full stack software engineer with a passion for crafting clean code and adhering to DRY principles. Javascript developer with experience assessing client needs, designing, building, testing, and deploying solutions while working in a fully distributed team. Former professional Broadway actor of 10 years totaling over 2,300 live performances from New York to Las Vegas. Excellent communicator with over 5 years experience mentoring young artists and athletes in both one-on-one and group settings.

## **SKILLS**

LANGUAGES: JavaScript, Node.js, Python, HTML, CSS, SQL, TypeScript

LIBRARIES AND FRAMEWORKS: React, Redux, Express, Flask, jQuery, Jest, React Testing Library, Bootstrap, Material UI

TOOLS: Git, AWS, PostgreSQL, VSCode, Heroku, Netlify, Jira

SOFT SKILLS: Public Speaking, Flexibility, Collaboration, Attention to detail

# **EXPERIENCE**

Zephyrx November 2021 - Current

Software Engineer · Remote

- · Led a team that rapidly deployed bespoke client solutions while instituting pair programming and code review, resulting in improved feature stability
- Oversaw conversion of React codebase from Javascript to Typescript, reducing reports of bugs in production
- · Constructed real-time video interface with AWS Kinesis and WebRTC, expanding clinical access to and usage of our real-time coaching feature
- · Formalized development processes by writing a company code style guide, leading to more concise version histories and clarifying expectations

May 2021 - November 2021

Associate Software Engineer · Remote

- · Assisted in implementation of real-time video and messaging via Amazon Chime, facilitating use of our dashboard for remote appointments
- Improved data flow by leveraging React-Redux to refactor state management, resulting in reduced page load times
- · Empowered our client services department by building out administrative tools, significantly reducing development team support workload

Technical Engineer, Jr. · Remote

November 2020 - May 2021

- Added accessibility for 20+ new languages, resulting in international use of our provider dashboard
- Supported QA team by developing a unit test suite and documentation, contributing to a single communication close rate over 75%
- Ensured production stability by coordinating testing of web and mobile components, improving team understanding of product

## Springboard, Software Engineering Career Track

Student

April 2020 - September 2020

- 700+ hours of hands-on course material
- 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight
- Completion of 4 in-depth portfolio projects
- · Mastered skills in front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, data structures and algorithms

Jersey Boys Actor · New York, NY August 2015 - March 2020

- Acted in over 1,500 performances of this ubiquitous Broadway Show
- Took action to save 7,800 ticket refunds over 4 performances by stepping in for duties outside of job scope

#### **PROJECTS**

Lyrify 2020

Lyrics for Spotify listeners

- Crafted a responsive single-page app with React, Redux, and Material UI components working with a Node / Express backend
- · Followed Oauth2 protocol for login via Spotify and consumed multiple 3rd party APIs for data aggregation with PostgreSQL
- · Improved MVP by adding custom search with input sanitization to increase rate of positive results

The Easy Meal 2020

Discover recipes, construct and email yourself a grocery list

- Built Flask Python backend serving dynamic Jinja HTML templates, and a UI responsively styled with bootstrap and custom CSS
- · Secured against CSRF with form validation, and applied bcrypt authentication for user registration and login
- Consumed 3rd party API to access over 380,000 recipes, and cached recipe data with PostgreSQL to reduce API calls.

Jobly 2020

Mock job-seeking website

- · Developed a RESTful API with Node / Express, and a modular UI for this single page React app
- Built and validated forms with Formik and JSONSchema, and managed data with PostgreSQL
- Followed JWT standard for user authentication and authorization

# **EDUCATION**

Springboard 2020 Software Engineering Career Track Certification Emerson College BFA Musical Theatre 2011 Cum Laude. Dean Scholarship Recipient